schlesingerassociates.com 2019-06-05

# See Our Privacy Policy & Privacy Shield Policy | Schlesinger Group

### Purpose

This privacy policy focuses on our data protection commitment to active and prospective marketing research clients and how we collect, store and process and transfer personal information for our direct marketing and communication purposes. (For our policy relating to marketing research, please see our [_Marketing Research Privacy Policy._](https://www.schlesingergroup.com/en/legal/privacy/#privacy-policy))

### Personal Information that is collected

**Information you submit**  
When you complete a form on our website or contact us to request a bid we ask you to provide your basic contact information.

When we meet you at an event or a private meeting, we invite you to provide your basic contact information.

When you confirm a project with us, we then ask you to provide billing information.

We retain any information collected in voluntary client surveys and feedback questionnaires.

**Cookies & Other Tracking Technology**  
Schlesinger Group and our analytics provider use standard internet technology such as cookies and Web beacons, ‘tag’ and ‘scripts’ as navigational information to track interactions with our websites on an individual and aggregated basis.

Our website and newsletters include social media features, such as the ‘Share’ button.  These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function. Social media features and widgets are hosted by a third party. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the social media company providing it.

### Children

The website is not intended for or targeted at children under the age of 16. And we do not knowingly or intentionally collect data about children under 16. If you believe we have collected information about a child under 16, please contact us at [ClientPrivacy@SchlesingerGroup.com](mailto:ClientPrivacy@SchlesingerGroup.com) so that we may delete the information.

### International Transfer of Personal Information

When you submit Personal Information, it is transferred to the United States to facilitate our global operations, and you hereby consent to such transfer which is protected in accordance with GDPR law and US Privacy Shield.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, please see our _Privacy Shield Policy._  Your Personal Information may also be stored and processed in any country where we have facilities or in which we engage service providers. Your data will be subject to the data transfer rules of that country and this privacy policy will still apply.

### How Personal Information is stored

Your information is stored in a central customer relationship management database in the United States. This leading database provider and its software has been DMA Privacy Shield certified.  Our project management, accounting and marketing automation software is used to process information from this system and is in turn governed by system security and strict data protection protocols.

We may disclose your Personal Information to any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries and holding companies for the purposes of or direct marketing or consolidating support services.

Schlesinger Group uses robust organizational, technical, and administrative measures to protect personal information within our company. This includes security controls to prevent unauthorized access to our systems. While we take reasonable steps to secure your personal information, please be aware that no transmission or security system

is guaranteed to be 100% secure from intrusion or hacking, and there is always some risk assumed by sharing Personal Information online. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure, please notify us immediately at [ClientPrivacy@SchlesingerGroup.com](mailto:ClientPrivacy@SchlesingerGroup.com).

### How Personal Information is Used

Schlesinger Group uses information you provide to communicate with you to help provide these services you request form us.

We may use this information to provide you with additional personalized information about company and partner news, services, promotions, events and content that we believe may be of interest to you.

If you provide us Personal Information about yourself or others, or if others give us your information, we will never share or sell that information for commercial purposes. We will only use that information for the specific reason for which it was provided to us.

**Information processors  
** We may provide your Personal Information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such e.communication processing or payment processing. These companies are authorized to use your Personal Information  _only as necessary to provide_  these services to us.

**Website**  
Schlesinger Group may use information collected to improve its websites and services and personalize your experience on our website and our communications so you don’t have to re-enter lots of information.  We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies.

**Testimonials**  
If you share a testimonial with us, with your permission we may post this on our website. You can update or remove your testimonial at any time by contacting us at [ClientPrivacy@SchlesingerGroup.com](mailto:ClientPrivacy@SchlesingerGroup.com).

**Links to other Websites**  
Our website includes links to other websites whose privacy practices may differ from our own.  Any Personal Information you submit to those sites, is governed by their privacy policies. We recommend you read the privacy policy of any website you visit.

**Changes in Ownership  
** If our company or our assets are acquired by another company, that company would receive all information collected by Schlesinger Group companies. In such an event, you would be notified by email or a prominent notice on our website of any changes of ownership, uses of your Personal Information and choices you have relating to your preferences.

**Compelled Disclosure**  
We reserve the right to disclose your Personal Information if required by law or if we believe use or disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud or comply with a law, court order or legal process.

### Communication of Preferences

We invite our clients and contacts in Europe  to consent or not consent to receiving marketing communications from Schlesinger Group companies.

Every marketing email contains information for users in any country on how to opt out of future marketing and non-transactional communications.

Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our website, but your ability to use some features or areas of our website may be restricted.

You may contact us to update or change your information.

You may request access to your information or request for your information to be deleted.

We have provided forms for you to communicate particular request so that we may consider and respond to your request in accordance with applicable law.

For your protection, we may only process requests with respect to the Personal Information associated with the particular email address that you use to send us your request. We may need to verify your identity before implementing your request. We will respond to your request within 30 days. We may need to retain certain information for record keeping purposes and/or to complete any transactions that you began prior to requesting such access, change or deletion.

### How to Contact Us Regarding Your Privacy

**Unsubscribing from marketing communications**  
If you wish to unsubscribe for marketing e.communications, you can do so [_here_](mailto:clientprivacy@schlesingergroup.com)

**Updating your personal information**  
To request that we correct or update any of your Personal Information, you can do so __[_here_](mailto:clientprivacy@schlesingergroup.com)

**Accessing your Personal Information**  
If you wish to request access to your personal information which we may hold, you may contact us _[here](mailto:clientprivacy@schlesingergroup.com)._

**Erasure of your Personal Information**  
If you wish to request for your Personal Information to be erased from our records, you may contact us _[here](mailto:clientprivacy@schlesingergroup.com)._

**General Inquiries, Concerns or Complaints relating to your Personal Information**  
If you wish to contact us about any matter relating to client privacy, you may contact us at [ClientPrivacy@SchlesingerGroup.com](mailto:ClientPrivacy@SchlesingerGroup.com) or write to us at Schlesinger Group, 101 Wood Avenue South, Iselin, NJ 08830. USA. Attention: Privacy Officer.

### Changes to this Policy

We may update this privacy policy to reflect changes to our information practices. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices to ensure they still meet with your approval.
